export const ANIMALHUSBANDRYA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. In farm animals, fertilization occurs in the",
A: "Cervix",
B: "Infundibulum",
C: "Ovary",
D: "Oviduct",
answer: "B. Infundibulum",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The main responsibility of farm hands in animal production is",
A: "Slaughtering of animals",
B: "Inspecting and grading of animals",
C: "Carrying out artificial insemination",
D: "Caring for animals",
answer: "D. Caring for animals",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following ingredients is required for teeth development in livestock?",
A: "Limestone",
B: "Yeast",
C: "Rock salt",
D: "Wheat bran",
answer: "A. Limestone",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Oxytocin is a hormone which",
A: "Aids in the contraction of the uterine muscles during parturition",
B: "Causes contraction of the pelvic ligaments during parturition",
C: "Helps in the production of heat in farm animals",
D: "Promotes sperm production through spermatogenesis",
answer: "A. Aids in the contraction of the uterine muscles during parturition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Deficiency of vitamin K",
A: "Causes night blindness",
B: "Causes rickets",
C: "Delays the clotting action of blood",
D: "Delays the onset of ovulation",
answer: "C. Delays the clotting action of blood",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Groundnut cake in animal feed supplies mainly",
A: "Carbohydrate",
B: "Fats",
C: "Protein",
D: "Vitamins",
answer: "C. Protein",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following conditions is not a result of low common salt intake in poultry?",
A: "Decreased appetite",
B: "Slow growth rate",
C: "Poor egg shell formation",
D: "feather pecking",
answer: "C. Poor egg shell formation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In a pig, salivary amylase converts",
A: "Starch to maltose",
B: "Protein to amino acids",
C: "Maltose to glucose",
D: "Fats to fatty acids and glycerol",
answer: "A. Starch to maltose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following hormones are female reproductive hormones?  \nI. Oestrogen  \nII. Relaxion  \nIII. Testosterone",
A: "I and II only",
B: "land III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The albumen of an egg is secreted in the",
A: "Infundibulum",
B: "Isthmus",
C: "Magnum",
D: "Uterus",
answer: "C. Magnum",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Feed can be prevented from growing mouldy by",
A: "Adding anti-oxidants to the feed",
B: "Keeping feed in Jute bags",
C: "Using well-dried feed ingredients",
D: "Mixing feed ingredients very well",
answer: "C. Using well-dried feed ingredients",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. An end product of herbage fermentation in the rumen is",
A: "Amino acids",
B: "Glucose",
C: "Glycerol",
D: "Volatile fatty acids",
answer: "D. Volatile fatty acids",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A zoonotic disease is one that",
A: "Is caused by micro-organisms",
B: "Spread quickly over a large area",
C: "Is transmissible from animals to humans",
D: "Can only be controlled by vaccination",
answer: "C. Is transmissible from animals to humans",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following organisms is an endoparasite of farm animals? `",
A: "Flea",
B: "Liver fluke",
C: "Mite",
D: "Tick",
answer: "B. Liver fluke",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A chick observed to have curled toes and reduced growth rate is likely to be suffering from a deficiency of",
A: "Vitamm B",
B: "Vitamin D",
C: "Vitamin E",
D: "Vitamin K",
answer: "A. Vitamin B",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Livestock are starved about 10 to 18 hours before the administration of dewormer",
A: "In order to kill the worms within a few hours",
B: "To ensure the livestock take in the dewormer",
C: "In order to reduce the quantity of dewormer required",
D: "To make it easier to restrain the animals",
answer: "B. To ensure the livestock take in the dewormer",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. An example of tick-borne diseases is",
A: "Anthrax",
B: "Babesiosis",
C: "Rinderpest",
D: "Trypanosomiasis",
answer: "B. Babesiosis",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A disease associated with the udder of ruminants is",
A: "Bloat",
B: "Coccidiosis",
C: "Enteritis",
D: "Mastitis",
answer: "D. Mastitis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Female animals willingly allow mating during",
A: "Libido",
B: "Oestrus",
C: "Ovulation",
D: "Puberty",
answer: "B. Oestrus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following statements about duck is correct",
A: "They are excellent foragers",
B: "They produce meat with low fat",
C: "They are prone to many pests and diseases",
D: "They are easy to rear under intensive system",
answer: "A. They are excellent foragers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The ideal ambient temperature for broiler chicks which are 9 days old is",
A: "20°C",
B: "25°C",
C: "30°C",
D: "35°C",
answer: "C. 30°C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Does are put on adequate nutrition one week before mating to",
A: "Minimize the mortality rate of embryos",
B: "Support the growth of the foetus",
C: "Increase the number of ova released",
D: "Produce sufficient milk for bunnies",
answer: "C. Increase the number of ova released",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. High percentage of hatchability is achieved when eggs to be incubated are kept for not more than",
A: "4 days",
B: "8 days",
C: "12 days",
D: "16 days",
answer: "B. 8 days",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The most effective way of controlling ectoparasites in laying birds is",
A: "Drenching",
B: "Dusting",
C: "Handpicking",
D: "Spraying",
answer: "B. Dusting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following conditions are required for successful incubation of eggs?  \nI. Turning of eggs  \nII. Suitable temperature  \nIII. High relative humidity",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following statements about broiler diet is correct?",
A: "Broiler finisher is fed in the first five weeks while broiler starter is fed between 5 and 8 weeks",
B: "Broiler starter has more vitamins than broiler finisher",
C: "Broiler starter has higher protein content than broiler finisher",
D: "Broiler starter has more trace elements than broiler finisher",
answer: "C. Broiler starter has higher protein content than broiler finisher",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following equipment can be used to castrate a piglet?",
A: "Burdizzo",
B: "Elastrator",
C: "Scalpel",
D: "Syringe",
answer: "C. Scalpel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In poultry production, straw is not suitable as a litter material because it",
A: "Breaks down easily",
B: "Is not absorbent enough",
C: "Makes the floor dirty",
D: "Impairs free movement of birds",
answer: "B. Is not absorbent enough",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The Rhode Island Red breed of fowl is a",
A: "Broiler breed",
B: "Game breed",
C: "Layer breed",
D: "Dual purpose breed",
answer: "D. Dual purpose breed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following signs are shown during oestrus in livestock?  \nI. Increased restlessness  \nII. Reduced body temperature  \nIII. Bellowing when isolated",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The Kuri is a breed of",
A: "Cattle",
B: "Goat",
C: "Pig",
D: "Sheep",
answer: "A. Cattle",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. If 100 broilers require 4.5 litres of water a day, how many litres of water would be required by 700 broilers?",
A: "1.30 litres",
B: "9.00 litres",
C: "15.75 litres",
D: "31.50 litres",
answer: "D. 31.50 litres",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following birds is a pet of high international reputation?",
A: "Eagle",
B: "Ostrich",
C: "Parrot",
D: "Penguin",
answer: "C. Parrot",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The average gestation period of a goat is",
A: "114 days",
B: "140 days",
C: "151 days",
D: "283 days",
answer: "C. 151 days",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The needle teeth of piglets are removed to",
A: "Make piglets grow healthier",
B: "Prevent piglets from biting one another",
C: "Prevent piglets from inflicting wounds on the teat of the sow",
D: "Allow piglets to suck sufficient milk form the sow",
answer: "C. Prevent piglets from inflicting wounds on the teat of the sow",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following conditions could lead to the clustering together of chicks under the hover?",
A: "Chlling",
B: "Ill-health",
C: "Over heating",
D: "Starvation",
answer: "A. Chilling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A breed of cattle that is trypanotolerant is",
A: "Muturu",
B: "Red Bororo",
C: "Sokoto Gudali",
D: "White Fulani",
answer: "A. Muturu",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Ruminants are able to break down roughage because",
A: "Their stomach is divided into four chambers",
B: "They secrete large amounts of ptyalin",
C: "Rumen microbes secrete the required enzymes",
D: "They have the capacity to chew the cud",
answer: "C. Rumen microbes secrete the required enzymes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A hog is a castrated",
A: "Boar",
B: "Buck",
C: "Bull",
D: "Ram",
answer: "A. Boar",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The young of a cat is called",
A: "Calf",
B: "Kid",
C: "Kitten",
D: "Puppy",
answer: "C. Kitten",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following structures in the egg serves as a source of nutrients for the developing embryo?",
A: "Albumen",
B: "Chalaza",
C: "Germ spot",
D: "Yolk",
answer: "D. Yolk",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. In order to prevent bloat cattle should not be",
A: "Fed on young succulent green legumes",
B: "Kept in a dirty environment",
C: "Fed on cereal grains",
D: "Kept in a cold environment",
answer: "A. Fed on young succulent green legumes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The weaning period of dairy cows is short because",
A: "Farmers need to collect milk for sale",
B: "The health of cows has to be protected",
C: "It prevents calves from certain diseases",
D: "Foster parents take better care of calves",
answer: "A. Farmers need to collect milk for sale",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A wedge shaped cattle with narrow shoulders could be a",
A: "Beef cattle",
B: "Cross-bred",
C: "Dairy cattle",
D: "Working bull",
answer: "C. Dairy cattle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. On a range land, legumes",
A: "Control weed growth",
B: "Control spread of diseases",
C: "Help increase fertility of the soil",
D: "Induce digestion in farm animals",
answer: "C. Help increase fertility of the soil",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. An example of browse plants is",
A: "Andropogon gayanus",
B: "Arachis hypogaea",
C: "Leucaena leucocephala",
D: "Vigna unguiculata",
answer: "C. Leucaena leucocephala",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following statements about natural pastures is correct?  \nI. They are poor in protein and minerals  \nII. They are abundant in the wet season  \nIII. They set seed early and become very fibrous",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Hutches should be located away from densely populated areas because rabbits",
A: "Have pests which are nuisance to humans",
B: "Are frightened by unusual noise",
C: "Produce too much waste material",
D: "May be stolen easily",
answer: "B. Are frightened by unusual noise",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Plants are grown in snail breeding paddocks in order to provide",
A: "Organic matter to make the soil fertile",
B: "Branches for snails to rest on",
C: "Places for snails to lay eggs",
D: "Shade for the snails",
answer: "D. Shade for the snails",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Mating of rabbits should take place in",
A: "The hutch of the buck",
B: "The hutch of the doe",
C: "A special mating hutch",
D: "A communal hutch",
answer: "A. The hutch of the buck",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]